# Kaio Fellipe

DevOps Engineer, Platform Engineer, SRE, Cloud Engineer

#### **Contacts**

LinkedIn: kaio-fellipe

### **Professional Profile**

Cloud/DevOps Engineer with over 8 years of experience in systems and technology analysis, working in the areas of Management, Architecture, DevOps, Infrastructure (On-premise and Cloud), Security and IT Services. Experience in Distributed Systems Architecture and Development projects, Business Intelligence, CRM, BPM, ERP implementation, ITIL, Office 365 and Infrastructure/Security standardization, following the best market practices. Experience in a national company in the Agribusiness segment, in the largest fashion tech company in Latin America and in the largest data analytics and artificial intelligence company for businesses in Latin America. I currently study and work with DevOps, Platform Engineering and Infrastructure as Code daily for the development of personal and professional projects.

### **Skills Summary**

DevOps, DevSecOps, Infrastructure as Code (IaC), Terraform, Terramate, Ansible, Crossplane, Packer, Google Cloud Platform (GCP), Network Architecture, BGP, Routing, IPSec, Hub & Spoke, AWS, Kubernetes, Helm, Microservices, Docker, GitOps, ArgoCD, Observability, Instana, Prometheus, Grafana Observability Stack, Zabbix, Linux, Service Mesh, Istio, GitHub, GitHub Actions, GitLab, GitLab CI, Progressive Rollouts, CI/CD, Cybersecurity, Cloud Security, Python, Bash Project Management, Infrastructure Management, Firewalls, REST API, Windows Servers, Virtualization, SQL, ETL Process, Business Intelligence.

### **Professional Experience**

#### Neoway (2 years +)

Senior DevOps/Cloud Engineer (Sep. 2022 - Present)

As a DevOps/Cloud Engineer in the largest data analytics and artificial intelligence company for businesses in Latin America, within the Engineering Productivity team, I deal daily with challenges to increasingly reduce the cognitive load of complex processes for all engineering, with a focus on platformization of internal services, based on that my day is divided into three work fronts.

- Cloud Infrastructure:
  - Linux

- GCP (GCE, GKE/Kubernetes, Memorystore, Microservices, Hub & Spoke, Cloud VPN, VPC Networks, IAM, IAP, GCS, Cloud DNS, Cloud NAT, Secret Manager, Cloud Monitoring, Cloud Logging, Billing)
- Infrastructure as Code (Terraform, Terramate, Ansible, Packer)
- Automation (Python, Bash, GNU Make, Docker)
- CDN
- Queues (Pub/Sub, RabbitMQ)
- Best security practices for cloud environments to maintain security certifications
  (ISO)

#### • Site reliability:

- Observability (Sysdig, Logit, ELK Stack, Opensearch, Prometheus, Grafana Observability Stack)
- Service Mesh with Istio/Anthos
- Progressive rollouts for zero downtime deployments
- Incident management and response
- Post-mortens
- Troubleshooting (mostly with USE method)

#### • Developer Experience:

- Backstage
- GitOps (ArgoCD)
- CI/CD with GitLab CI
- GitLab
- Helm
- Kustomize

### Dafiti Group (8 months)

• SysAdmin (Feb. 2022 - Sep. 2022)

As a SysAdmin at the largest fashion tech in Latin America, I was able to get to know the DevOps culture applied on a large scale, in addition to the administration of servers and clusters at EKS, I was able to participate in initiatives for continuous improvement of Observability and eCommerce incident handling.

- Linux
- GitOps (ArgoCD)
- Puppet (laC)
- Transact-SQL
- Troubleshooting
- AWS (EC2, RDS, S3, EKS, Route53, ECS, IAM, etc)
- Python, Bash
- Distributed Systems and multi-platform apps
- Observability (ELK Stack, Instana, Zabbix, Grafana, Graylog)
- CDN (Azion)
- Queue systems (RabbitMQ)

- Cache systems (Memcached)
- GitHub
- o CI/CD

#### Safra Rica (5 years and 6 months)

• IT Analyst (Jul. 2019 - Feb. 2022)

As an IT Analyst, I was able to lead and participate in some projects such as: standardization of the entire infrastructure of all our branches, implementation of the BPM methodology in the accounting and commercial area, implementation of the virtualized server infrastructure, and the implementation of a data warehouse created by my team.

- I worked as:
  - Team Leader (Manager)
  - SQL Database management and administration
  - SQL development and data analysis for Business Intelligence
  - ETL development
  - IT Project Leader
  - Business process management
  - Linux and Windows Server Management/Administration
  - Network Management/Administration
  - Firewall Management/Administration
  - Data Center Management/Administration
  - N2 and N3 Support
  - Hardward maintenance and troubleshooting
- I worked with:
  - Windows Server
  - Linux Servers
  - Transact-SQL, Python, Bash, PowerShell
  - MySQL, PostgreSQL, Firebird
  - BI tools
  - Data Warehouses
  - ETL tools (Python SDKs)
  - Monitoring systems (Zabbix, Grafana)
  - CRM softwares
  - ERPs
  - pfSense, Sophos, Mikrotik
  - Network devices (Cisco, Ubiquiti, TP-Link)
  - Network configuration and troubleshooting (VLANs, VPNs, routing, firewall, etc)
  - Networking protocols and services (TCP, UDP, IP, ARP, ICMP, DNS, DHCP, NAT, VPN, VLAN, BGP, IPSec, HTTP, HTTPS, SSH, FTP, telnet, etc)
  - Anti-virus and anti-malware solutions
  - Security awareness training
- IT Technician (Oct. 2017 Jun. 2019)

As an IT Technician, I was able to lead some projects such as: data center infrastructure readjustment, ERP migration, BI structuring, CRM software implementation, among others.

- Development of dashboards for analysis using SQL
- Database Administration
- Firewall Administration
- N2 and N3 Support
- Network Administration
- Local Systems Administration
- Windows Server Administration
- Other administrative activities...
- Intern (Aug. 2016 Sep. 2017)

As an intern, I managed to implement the first firewall used in the company, deploying a proxy and an IDS/IPS together, a significant gain in connection quality and security was noted.

- Computer Maintenance
- Firewall Configuration and Maintenance
- N1 and N2 Support
- Network Maintenance
- Requirements Analysis for Process Improvements
- Local Systems Administration
- Windows Server Maintenance
- Other administrative activities...

### Languages

Portuguese: NativeEnglish: Advanced

### **Educational Background**

**IGTI** (2019 - 2020)

MBA in IT Management

**Senac** (2018 - 2020)

Postgraduate in Information Security

**Unifafibe** (2013 - 2017)

Bachelor's Degree in Information Systems

#### Certificates

**DevOps Training** (2022)

- Track from Alura covering the following topics:
  - Terraform
  - Ansible
  - Vagrant
  - Observability
  - CI/CD
  - Kubernetes
  - Docker

## GitOps at Scale (2022)

Codefresh

## GitOps Fundamentals (2022)

Codefresh

## **Python Certificate** (2022)

• HackerRank

## **SQL (Advanced) Certificate** (2022)

HackerRank

## **CSFPC** (2021)

• Cyber Security Foundation Professional Certificate by CertiProf

## **SFPC** (2020)

• Scrum Foundation Professional Certificate by CertiProf